Guide to the James Weldon Johnson and Grace Nail Johnson Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1896-1972; Series I; 18.14; (46 boxes)
  - Grace Nail Johnson Correspondence, 1910-73
    - "Ea-Ez" General (Box 28, Folder 55)
      To: 30 / From: 2
    - Egypt, Ophelia Settle, 1972-1976 (Box 28, Folder 55a)
    - Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers), 1932-50 (Box 28, Folder 56)
    - Ernst, Morris Leopold, 1963, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 57)
    - "Fa-Fz" General (Box 28, Folder 58)
      To: 36 / From: 4
    - Fairclough, Alice B., 1944 (Box 28, Folder 59)
      Includes 102 letters from students thanking GNJ for visiting their school
    - Fairservis, Mildred, 1950-72, undated (Box 28, Folder 60)
    - Fauset, Jessie Redmon, 1921, 1938, undated (Box 28, Folder 61)
    - Fauset, Crystal Dreda Bird, 1933-34 (Box 28, Folder 62)
    - Fax, Elton C., 1946 (Box 28, Folder 63)
    - Franklin, John Hope, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 64)
    - Frazier, Marie B., 1932-50 (Box 28, Folder 65)
    - Fuller, Meta Warrick, 1917, 1920 (Box 28, Folder 66)
    - "Ga-Gh" General (Box 29, Folder 67)
      To: 17 / From: 2
    - Gannett, Lewis, 1938-67 (Box 29, Folder 68)
      Includes correspondence with Ruthy Gannett Kahn
    - "Gi-Gz" General (Box 29, Folder 69)
      To: 27 / From: 4
    - Gilbert, Ethel Bedient, 1932 (Box 29, Folder 70)
    - Grant, Frances, 1940-70, undated (Box 29, Folder 71)
    - Green-Wood Cemetery (New York, N.Y.), 1947-1977 (Box 29, Folder 71a)
      Includes photographs of Nail plot and gravestones
    - Guggenheim Foundation, 1940-53 (Box 29, Folder 72)
    - "Ha-Hd" General (Box 29, Folder 73)
    - Hall, Juanita, 1938-68, undated (Box 29, Folder 74)
    - Handy, William C., 1939-58, undated (Box 29, Folder 75)
      Includes material re: Handy
    - Harcourt Brace & Company
      See: Harcourt Brace & Company
    - Harrington, Oliver, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 76)
    - Haynes, George Edmund, 1953-54 (Box 29, Folder 77)
    - Haynes, Mrs. George Edmund (Olyve L. Jeter), 1938-71 (Box 29, Folder 78)
    - Hays, Arthur Garfield, 1939-55 (Box 29, Folder 79)
    - "He-Hl" General (Box 29, Folder 80)
      To: 27 / From: 6
    - Himes, Ida, 1950-73 (Box 29, Folder 81)
      To: 18 / From: 1
    - Himes, Ida, 1968-72 (Box 29, Folder 82)
    - "Ho-Ht" General (Box 30, Folder 83)
      To: 19 / From: 2
    - Holden, Marian, 1936-67, undated (Box 30, Folder 84)
    - Hope, Mrs. John, 1934-42, undated (Box 30, Folder 85)
    - Howe, Marie Jenny, 1918-27, undated (Box 30, Folder 86)
    - "Hu-Hz" General (Box 30, Folder 87)
      To: 15 / From: 0
    - Hughes, Langston, 1941-67, undated (Box 30, Folder 88)
    - Hull, Elizabeth Shaffer, 1932-37 (Box 30, Folder 89)
      To: 22 / From: 0
    - Huyck, Laura Talmage, 1929-55, undated (Box 30, Folder 90)
    - "Ia-Iz" General (Box 30, Folder 91)
    - International House, 1939 (Box 30, Folder 92)
    - Interracial Youth Committee, 1945-46 (Box 30, Folder 93)
      Includes reports, press releases, etc.
    - "Ja-Jz" General (Box 30, Folder 94-94a)
      To: 36 / From: 6
    - Jackman, Harold, 1940-61 (Box 30, Folder 95)
    - Jeter, Olyve L.
      See: Haynes, Mrs. George Edmund, Box 9, folder 201
    - Johnson, Charles S., 1935-56, undated (Box 30, Folder 96)
      To: 14 / From: 6
    - Johnson, Georgia Douglas Camp, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 97)
    - James Weldon Johnson Birthday Celebration, in memory, 1942 (Box 30, Folder 98)
      Letters received by the Committee
    - James Weldon Johnson Community Center, 1949-69 (Box 30, Folder 99)
    - James Weldon Johnson Homes, Philadelphia, Pa., 1940-41 (Box 31, Folder 100)
      Includes correspondence re: Grace Nail Johnson Girl Scout Troop
    - James Weldon Johnson Houses, New York, N.Y., 1946-48 (Box 31, Folder 101)
      Includes 19 photos
    - James Weldon Johnson Literary Guild, 1939-53, n.d (Box 31, Folder 102)
    - James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection, Beinecke Library, Yale University
      - General, 1947-76 (Box 31, Folder 103)
      - James T. Babb, 1944-65 (Box 31, Folder 104)
        To: 24 / From: 6
      - Donald Gallup, 1949-66, undated (Box 31, Folder 105)
        To: 24 / From: 9
      - Charles Seymour, 1950 (Box 31, Folder 106)
      - Charles Seymour, 1965-68 (Box 31, Folder 107)
        Requests to use A-H
      - Charles Seymour, 1952-69 (Box 31, Folder 108)
        Requests to use I-Z
        To: 19 / From: 7
    - James Weldon Johnson Party, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 109)
      Re: re-publication of Autobiography of an Ex- Colored Man
    - James Weldon Johnson School, 1963, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 110)
      Elementary school, Chicago, Illinois
    - James Weldon Johnson School, 1966-67 (Box 31, Folder 111)
      Elementary school, New York, N.Y.
    - James Weldon Johnson School, 1955 (Box 31, Folder 112)
      Junior high school, Jacksonville, Florida
    - James Weldon Johnson School, 1964-65 (Box 31, Folder 113)
      High school, Yorktown, Va.
    - James Weldon Johnson, testimonials in memoriam, c. 1938 (Box 31, Folder 114)
    - Johnson, John H., 1946 (Box 31, Folder 115)
    - Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1964 (Box 31, Folder 116)
    - Johnson, Mordecai W. (Mordecai Wyatt), 1932, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 117)
    - Jones, Eugene Kinckle, 1938-54 (Box 31, Folder 118)
    - Jones, Mrs. Thomas E., 1931-39, undated (Box 31, Folder 119)
      Includes correspondence with Thomas E. Jones
    - Juger, Esther, [1938], undated (Box 31, Folder 120)
    - "Ka-Kz" General (Box 32, Folder 121)
      To: 30 / From: 5
    - Kaplan, Kivie, 1962-63 (Box 32, Folder 122)
    - Kellog, Charles Flint, 1949-67 (Box 32, Folder 123)
    - Kennedy, Jacqueline, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 124)
    - Kibble, Florence K., 1942-48 (Box 32, Folder 125)
      To: 23 / From: 3
    - Kibble, Florence K., 1949-55, undated (Box 32, Folder 126)
      To: 25 / From: 4
    - Knopf, Alfred A., 1940-67 (Box 32, Folder 127)
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc.
      See: James Weldon Johnson Series
    - Knopf, Alfred A. Jr. ("Pat"), 1938, 1940, undated (Box 32, Folder 128)
    - Knopf, Blanche W., 1934-66, undated (Box 32, Folder 129)
    - Knox, John, 1934, 1943, undated (Box 32, Folder 130)
    - "La-Lh" General (Box 32, Folder 131)
      To: 27 / From: 3
      Includes photographs of Sam Lee, Irma Lee, Crystal Bard Fauset and others
    - LaFarge, John, 1935-65 (Box 32, Folder 132)
      Includes correspondence re: LaFarge
    - LaFarge, Mrs. Oliver, 1933-34 (Box 32, Folder 133)
    - LaFollette, Fola, 1938, undated (Box 32, Folder 134)
    - La Guardia, Fiorello H. (Fiorello Henry), 1947 (Box 32, Folder 135)
    - Lampkin, Daisy E. (Daisy Elizabeth), 1938-65 (Box 32, Folder 136)
    - Larsen, Nella, undated (Box 32, Folder 137)
    - Lee, Charles ("Canada"), 1953 (Box 32, Folder 138)
      Correspondence re: Lee
    - Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1949 (Box 32, Folder 139)
    - "Li-Lz" General (Box 32, Folder 140)
    - Library of Congress, 1939-1976 (Box 32, Folder 141)
    - Lieberson, Goddard, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 142)
    - Locke, Alain LeRoy, 1941-42 (Box 32, Folder 143)
    - Logan, Rayford Whittingham, 1942 (Box 32, Folder 144)
      Includes: Best, Marshall A. 1/0 letters (copy) with Rayford Logan 1942 Nov 30
    - "Ma-Md" General (Box 33, Folder 145-145a)
      To: 39 / From: 4
    - Mabry, Tom, 1938, undated (Box 33, Folder 146)
    - McKay, Claude, 1938-42, n.d (Box 33, Folder 147)
    - Marinoff, Fania
      See: Van Vechten, Carl and Van Vechten, Fania Marinoff, Box 37, folder 237
    - May, Ethel, 1910, 1912 (Box 33, Folder 148)
    - "Me-Mz" General (Box 33, Folder 149)
      Includes letter from Lewis Mumford
      To: 23 / From: 6
    - Megali, P. Richard, 1939-72, undated (Box 33, Folder 150)
      To: 13 / From: 0
    - Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1942-56 (Box 33, Folder 151)
      To: 5 / From: 4
    - Meyer, Annie Nathan, 1931-41, undated (Box 33, Folder 152)
    - Miller, Fredrick H., 1933-39 (Box 33, Folder 153)
    - Miller, Lucile V., 1931-56, undated (Box 33, Folder 154)
    - Mitchell, Mrs. Clarence M. (Juanita Jackson), 1938, 1962 (Box 33, Folder 155)
    - Moon, Henry Lee, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 156)
    - William Morrow and Company, 1963, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 157)
    - Morse, Leila Livingston, 1932, 1941, undated (Box 33, Folder 158)
    - Mwalimu School, 1937, 1939 (Box 33, Folder 159)
      Correspondence with Manet Harrison-Fowler
    - Myers, Gordon, 1965-72 (Box 33, Folder 160)
    - "Na-Nz" General (Box 33, Folder 161)
    - Napier, James Carroll, 1932, 1938 (Box 33, Folder 162)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1938-69 (Box 33, Folder 163)
      Correspondence with National Office and local branches
    - National Association of Colored Graduate Nurses, 1938-51, undated (Box 33, Folder 164)
      Includes correspondence with Mabel K. Staupers
    - National Broadcasting Co., Inc., 1943-53 (Box 33, Folder 165)
    - Negro Actors Guild of America, 1939 (Box 33, Folder 166)
    - New American Library, 1948-54 (Box 33, Folder 167)
    - New York (N.Y.). Dept. of Education, 1964-1966 (Box 33, Folder 167a)
    - "Oa-Oz" General (Box 34, Folder 168)
    - Okala, Ollie Jewell Sims, 1934-70, undated (Box 34, Folder 169)
      Includes draft of letter from GNJ regarding burial arrangements
    - Okala, Ollie Jewell Sims, 1968-72 (Box 34, Folder 170)
      Cards sent to GNJ
    - Okala, Ollie Jewell Sims, 1943-67 (Box 34, Folder 171)
      cards sent to GNJ
    - Ottley, Roi, 1943 (Box 34, Folder 172)
    - Ovington, Mary White, 1915-47, undated (Box 34, Folder 173)
      To: 25 / From: 2
    - "Pa-Pn" General (Box 34, Folder 174)
      To: 25 / From: 5
    - Parsons, Elsie Worthington Clews, 1918-22 (Box 34, Folder 175)
    - Parsons, Herbert E., 1922 (Box 34, Folder 176)
    - Patterson, Fredrick Douglas, 1954-66 (Box 34, Folder 177)
    - Payne, E. George (Enoch George), 1938-46 (Box 34, Folder 178)
      Includes correspondence with Mrs. George E. Payne
    - Peterson, Dorothy, 1932-51, undated (Box 34, Folder 179)
    - Petry, Ann, 1945, undated (Box 34, Folder 180)
    - Phylon, undated (Box 34, Folder 181)
    - Pickens, William, 1934-40 (Box 34, Folder 182)
    - Pitt, Mary Lee, 1939-71 (Box 34, Folder 183)
    - "Po-Pz" General (Box 34, Folder 184)
    - Pollock, Helen Channing, 1953-55 (Box 34, Folder 185)
    - Price, Leontyne, 1961, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 186)
    - "Qa-Qz" General (Box 34, Folder 187)
    - "Ra-Rg" General (Box 35, Folder 188)
    - Randolph, Bertha B., 1932-56 (Box 35, Folder 189)
      To: 19 / From: 1
    - Randolph, Richetta G., 1919-70 (Box 35, Folder 190)
    - "Rh-Rz" General (Box 35, Folder 191)
      To: 30 / From: 3
    - Robeson, Eslanda Goode, 1930, 1953, undated (Box 35, Folder 192)
    - Robinson, A'Lelia Walker
    - Robinson, Bill ("Bojangles"), 1948 (Box 35, Folder 193)
    - Robinson, Jackie, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 194)
    - Rockefeller, John D., 1939, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 195)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1938, 1942 (Box 35, Folder 196)
    - Rowan, Carl T. (Carl Thomas), 1966-67 (Box 35, Folder 197)
    - "Sa-Sc" General (Box 35, Folder 198)
    - Sandburg, Carl, 1951 (Box 35, Folder 199)
    - Sands, Diana, 1965 (Box 35, Folder 200)
    - Savage, Augusta, 1939 (Box 35, Folder 201)
    - Schoenrich, Otto, 1938, 1945 (Box 35, Folder 202)
    - Schuyler, George S. (George Samuel), 1965-70 (Box 35, Folder 203)
    - Scott, Emmett J. (Emmett Jay), 1938, 1947 (Box 35, Folder 204)
    - "Se-Sl" General (Box 35, Folder 205)
    - Seligmann, Herbert J. (Herbert Jacob), 1965 (Box 35, Folder 206)
    - Shaffer, Van Vechten, 1938-72, undated (Box 35, Folder 207)
    - Silvera, Frank, 1961 (Box 35, Folder 208)
    - Sissle, Noble, 1953-54 (Box 35, Folder 209)
    - "Sm-Sp" General (Box 35, Folder 210)
    - Song Writers' Protective Association
      See: Box 19, folder 446
    - Spencer, Anne, 1933-71 (Box 35, Folder 211)
      Includes correspondence with Chauncey Spencer
    - Spingarn, Amy, 1932, 1934, undated (Box 35, Folder 212)
    - Spingarn, Arthur B. (Arthur Barnett), 1922-71 (Box 35, Folder 213)
    - Spingarn, Hope, 1934 (Box 35, Folder 214)
    - Spingarn, Joel Elias, 1934-39 (Box 35, Folder 215)
      Includes correspondence of Honor Spingarn
    - "St-Sz" General (Box 36, Folder 216)
      To: 24 / From: 1
    - Staupers, Mabel Keaton
    - Stern, Mrs. Alfred K., 1933 (Box 36, Folder 217)
    - Stone, Mrs. Cecil Hollis, 1939 (Box 36, Folder 218)
    - Studin, Charles H., 1938 (Box 36, Folder 219)
    - Sutton, Percy E., 1969 (Box 36, Folder 220)
    - "Ta-Tg" General (Box 36, Folder 221)
    - Talbert, Mary B.
    - Tarry, Ellen, 1942-57 (Box 36, Folder 222)
    - Tarry, Ellen, 1963-73 (Box 36, Folder 223)
    - "Th" General (Box 36, Folder 224)
    - Thomas, Edna, 1966-68 (Box 36, Folder 225)
    - Thomas, Helen, 1938-50 (Box 36, Folder 226)
    - Thomas, Helen, 1954-72 (Box 36, Folder 227)
    - "Ti-Tz" General (Box 36, Folder 228)
      To: 15 / From: 2
    - Tobias, Channing H., 1938-55 (Box 36, Folder 229)
    - Towns, George A. (George Alexander), 1942-52, undated (Box 36, Folder 230)
    - Twentieth Century Fund, 1943 (Box 36, Folder 231)
    - "Ua-Uz" General (Box 36, Folder 232)
    - Uggams, Leslie, 1967 (Box 36, Folder 233)
    - Untermeyer, Louis, 1940-70 (Box 36, Folder 234)
    - "Va-Vz" General (Box 37, Folder 235)
      To: 21 / From: 2
    - Van Doren, Irita Taylor, 1950-67 (Box 37, Folder 236)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1925, 1929 (Box 37, Folder 237)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1931-38 (Box 37, Folder 238)
      Includes photographs of Van Vechten, Marinoff, Johnson, and others
      To: 36 / From: 3
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1939 (Box 37, Folder 239)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1940-42 (Box 37, Folder 240)
      To: 12 / From: 1
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 241)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1946 (Box 37, Folder 242)
      To: 24 / From: 0
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1947-49 (Box 37, Folder 243)
      To: 29 / From: 0
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1950-58 (Box 37, Folder 244)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1961-64 (Box 37, Folder 245)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, undated (Box 37, Folder 246)
      Includes photos and miscellaneous clippings re: Fania Marinoff
    - Carl Van Vechten Dinner, 1942 (Box 37, Folder 247)
      Copies of correspondence received by Roberta Bosley
    - Van Vechten, Fania Marinoff, 1965-67 (Box 37, Folder 248)
      Includes: Schuyler, George S. 0/1 letters (photo copy) with Fania Marinoff Van Vechten 1964 Dec 23
    - Virginia Union University (Richmond, Va.), 1972 (Box 37, Folder 248a)
    - "Wa-Wd" General (Box 38, Folder 249)
    - Wagner, Robert F. (Robert Ferdinand), 1938-65 (Box 38, Folder 250)
    - Walker, A'Lelia, 1922 (Box 38, Folder 251)
    - Washington, Eleanor, 1938-47 (Box 38, Folder 252)
    - "We-Wi" General (Box 38, Folder 253-253a)
      To: 46 / From: 2
    - Weaver, Robert, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 254)
    - Webster, Edgar H., 1940 (Box 38, Folder 255)
    - Wertheim, Alma, 1932, undated (Box 38, Folder 256)
    - White, Clarence Cameron, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 257)
    - White, Jane, 1957, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 258)
    - White, Walter Francis, 1934-47 (Box 38, Folder 259)
      Includes: Mitchell, Mrs. Clarence M. 0/1 letters (copy) with Walter White 1938 Dec 2
    - White, Poppy Cannon, 1955, undated (Box 38, Folder 260)
    - Wilkins, Roy, 1938-72 (Box 38, Folder 261)
    - Wilkinson, Henry B., 1938 (Box 38, Folder 262)
    - "Wo-Wz" General (Box 38, Folder 263)
    - Wood, L. Hollingsworth (Levi Hollingsworth), 1934-47 (Box 38, Folder 264)
    - Woolston, Florence G., 1919 (Box 38, Folder 265)
    - Wright, Louis T. (Louis Tompkins), 1947 (Box 38, Folder 266)
    - Wright, Richard, 1940-41, undated (Box 38, Folder 267)
    - "X, Y, Z" General (Box 38, Folder 268)
      To: 12 / From: 0
    - Yale University
      See: James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection, Beinecke Library, Yale University
    - Yerby, Frank, 1946 (Box 38, Folder 269)
    - Y.M.C.A. and Y.W.C.A., 1947-72, undated (Box 38, Folder 270)
    - Zangrando, Robert, 1962-66 (Box 38, Folder 271)
      To: 10 / From: 6
    - Greeting cards, circa 1960-1970 (Box 39, Folder 271a-271e)
    - Unidentified correspondents (Box 39, Folder 272)
      To: 23 / From: 0
    - Unidentified correspondents (Box 39, Folder 273)
      To: 36 / From: 2
    - Unidentified correspondents (Box 39, Folder 274)
      Includes empty envelopes
    - Drafts of letters written by Grace Nail Johnson and notes, circa 1950-1970 (Box 39a, Folder 274a-274c)
  - Family Correspondence, 1864-1969
    The Family Correspondence is organized under the following ten headings: Letters Received by James Weldon Johnson, Letters Received by Grace Nail Johnson, Letters Received by James Johnson, Letters Received by Agnes M. Edwards, Letters Received by J. Rosamond Johnson, Letters Received by Mildred L. Johnson, Letters Received by John B. Nail, Letters Received by Mrs. John B. Nail, Letters Received by John E. Nail, and Letters Received by Mrs. John E. Nail. Under each heading the correspondence is arranged alphabetically by the name of the writer of the letter.
    The Family Correspondence is made up of letters exchanged between the Johnsons and their families as well as letters exchanged between other family members. This subseries also contains miscellaneous correspondence received by family members from third parties.
    Family Correspondence is small but focuses on aspects of Johnson's activities not treated in the first two subseries and gives information about activities of important members of his family. The correspondence between Johnson and his wife prior to 1920 is both extensive and rich. It covers Johnson's consular work in Corinto, the problems incurred in settling his father's estate, and his second attempt at lyric writing. The correspondence between Johnson and his wife also gives their private insights into many of his activities. The correspondence between Johnson and his brother J. Rosamond Johnson is particularly descriptive of the latter's career in musical comedy and musical comedy stage. The subseries also contains some letters written to John B. Nail and John E. Nail, who were prominent in New York finance and real estate.
    - Letters Received by James Weldon Johnson
      - from Stephen A. Dillet, 1917-33 (Box 40, Folder 1)
        Includes correspondence with Lillian C. Dillet and Helen Louise Dillet
        Number: 8
      - from Agnes M. Edwards, 1915-29 (Box 40, Folder 2)
        Includes joint letters with Helen Louise Johnson and miscellaneous material re: death of AME
        Number: 13
      - from Grace Nail Johnson, 1907-09 (Box 40, Folder 3)
        Number: 9
      - from Grace Nail Johnson, 1910-13 (Box 40, Folder 4)
        Number: 10
      - from Grace Nail Johnson, 1914 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - from Grace Nail Johnson, 1916, 1918 (Box 40, Folder 6)
        Number: 5
      - from Grace Nail Johnson, 1923-29 (Box 40, Folder 7)
        Number: 17
      - from Grace Nail Johnson, 1931-36 (Box 40, Folder 8)
        Number: 11
      - from Grace Nail Johnson, undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
        Number: 6
      - from Helen Louise Johnson, 1912-19, undated (Box 40, Folder 10)
        Includes miscellaneous items re: funeral of HLJ
      - from J. Rosamond Johnson, 1912, 1913 Jun (Box 40, Folder 11)
        Number: 7
      - from J. Rosamond Johnson, 1913 Aug-Dec (Box 40, Folder 12)
      - from J. Rosamond Johnson, 1920-32 (Box 40, Folder 13)
        Includes letters undated, but seem to be c. 1930-32
        Number: 25
      - from J. Rosamond Johnson, 1933-38, undated (Box 40, Folder 14)
        Includes letters from Nora Johnson
        Number: 38
      - from Mildred L. Johnson, 1932 (Box 40, Folder 15)
        Number: 2
      - from John B. Nail, 1916 (Box 40, Folder 16)
      - from John E. Nail, 1911-34 (Box 40, Folder 17)
        Number: 15
    - Letters Received by Grace Nail Johnson
      - from Agnes M. Edwards, 1912 (Box 41, Folder 18)
        Number: 1
      - from Lottie Griffin and Josephine Miller, 1910, undated (Box 41, Folder 19)
      - from Helen Louise Johnson, 1911-1912, undated (Box 41, Folder 20)
        Number: 3
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1912 Mar-May (Box 41, Folder 21)
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1912 Jun-Aug (Box 41, Folder 22)
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1912 Sep-Dec (Box 41, Folder 23)
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1914 (Box 41, Folder 24)
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1916 (Box 41, Folder 25)
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1918, 1919 (Box 41, Folder 26)
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1920 (Box 41, Folder 27)
      - from James Weldon Johnson, c. 1920 (Box 41, Folder 28)
        Post cards from Haiti
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1922-23 (Box 41, Folder 29)
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1925-28 (Box 41, Folder 30)
        Number: 20
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1929 Jun-Oct 2 (Box 41, Folder 31)
        Number: 16
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1929 Oct 4-Dec (Box 41, Folder 32)
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 33)
        Copies of letters from Japan
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1932, 1933 (Box 41a, Folder 34)
        Number: 18
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1934, 1935 (Box 41a, Folder 35)
        Number: 19
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1936-38 (Box 41a, Folder 36)
        Number: 28
      - from James Weldon Johnson, undated (Box 41a, Folder 37)
        Includes fragments and envelopes
      - from J. Rosamond Johnson, 1910-54, undated (Box 42, Folder 38)
        Number: 21
      - from Mildred L. Johnson, 1933-69 (Box 42, Folder 39)
      - from Grayce Fairfax Nail, 1942-45 (Box 42, Folder 39a)
      - from John B. Nail, 1914-38, undated (Box 42, Folder 40)
        Number: 14
      - from Mrs. John B. Nail, undated (Box 42, Folder 41)
        Fragment
      - from John E. Nail, 1914-38 (Box 42, Folder 42)
      - from Mrs. John E. Nail, 1938-68 (Box 42, Folder 43)
        Number: 12
    - Letters Received by James Johnson
      - from James Weldon Johnson and from miscellaneous correspondents, 1864, 1913, undated (Box 42, Folder 44)
      - material re: the estate of, 1901-19 (Box 42, Folder 45)
        Miscellaneous bills, rent statements, mortgages and contracts
        Number: 46
    - Letters Received by Agnes M. Edwards
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1915 (Box 42, Folder 46)
      - from miscellaneous correspondents, 1925 (Box 42, Folder 47)
    - Letters Received by J. Rosamond Johnson
      - from Helen Louise Johnson, 1912 (Box 42, Folder 48)
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1932-38 (Box 42, Folder 49)
      - royalty statements, 1912-17 (Box 42, Folder 50)
        Number: 50
      - from miscellaneous correspondents, 1913-51, undated (Box 42, Folder 51-51a)
        Includes: Hughes, Langston 0/1 letter (note of congratulations) with J. Rosamond Johnson c. 1951
        Includes letters of condolence re: death of JWJ
        Number: 117
    - Letters Received by Mildred L. Johnson
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1932, 1936 (Box 42, Folder 52)
      - from Grace Nail Johnson, 1954 (Box 42, Folder 53)
      - from miscellaneous correspondents, 1938 (Box 42, Folder 54)
        Letters of condolence re: death of JWJ
    - Letters Received by John B. Nail
      - from Grace Nail Johnson, 1912-42, undated (Box 42, Folder 55)
        Number: 4
      - from miscellaneous correspondents, 1893-1936 (Box 42, Folder 56)
        Includes: Ransom, Reverdy 0/1 letters with John B. Nail 1911 Aug 28
        Includes: Root, Elihu 0/1 letters with John B. Nail 1913 Aug 26
        Number: 27
      - stock certificates owned by JBN (Box 42, Folder 57)
    - Letters Received by Mrs. John B. Nail
      - from James Weldon Johnson (Box 42, Folder 58)
    - Letters Received by John E. Nail
      - from James Weldon Johnson, 1912-34 (Box 42, Folder 59)
      - from Grace Nail Johnson, 1914 (Box 42, Folder 60)